#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/ michellevenables21 (LinkedIn)

#### Top Skills

Data Analysis

Python (Programming Language)

SQL

# Michelle Venables

Data Scientist and Machine Learning Engineer Laguna Beach, California

### Summary

Data Scientist and Machine Learning Engineer with experience in Data Acquisition, Predictive Modeling, Statistical Analysis, Machine Learning, and Natural Language Processing. With 2 years of experience in Financial Consulting and a Master's in Business Administration, I am excited to advance my career in Data Science in order to effectively solve business problems. I have a passion for learning and hope to be part of a team of experienced Engineers and Data Scientists!

## Experience

HBMJ Consulting, LLC

Associate

October 2017 - September 2019 (2 years)

Performed data analysis on multiple areas of the business including profit and loss statements, monthly and quarterly reconciliation processes, and annual financial statements.

Fulfilled project management tasks of 2 upgrades with the Advent Geneva's Accounting Software while working with Data Scientists and Software Engineers to identify enhancements on custom reports.

Provided software and accounting support to all clients with the responsibility of delivering weekly status reports.

Villanova University
MBA Graduate and Research Fellow
August 2015 - August 2017 (2 years 1 month)
Villanova, PA

Experience assisting two professors with their duties in conducting research involving data collection in business management and marketing.

Responsible for creating a presentation to speak at the Journal of Public Policy and Marketing Conference.

Merrill Lynch Seasonal Client Associate June 2015 - August 2015 (3 months) New York, NY

Worked with the Investment Strategy Team, providing operational support and due diligence reports of asset managers for client portfolio selection.

Cendyn

Digital Marketing Intern November 2014 - February 2015 (4 months)

Boca Raton, Florida

SEO, Paid Search

Fendi Marketing Internship June 2013 - August 2013 (3 months)

#### Education

Flatiron School
Data Science · (2019)

Villanova University

Master of Business Administration (M.B.A.), Strategic Management, Analytics, and Marketing · (2015 - 2017)

Florida Atlantic University

Bachelor's Degree, Finance, General · (2011 - 2015)

The American University of Rome Study Abroad, Finance, General · (2013 - 2013)